Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today
we have a sad lesson for you.
This is an intermediate
level lesson
about what happens when a
friend or family member dies.
Exactly. So we have a lot
of words that are related
to all the preparations
for when somebody dies.
And also, some phrases that
you can say to someone that
maybe had a family member
who recently passed away.
So before we get into all
of this, we have a keyword
that we want to take a look
at now in vocabulary preview.
Very vocabulary preview.
Alright, so in vocabulary
preview you have that
one word and it's the
title of our lesson also,
Funeral. Funeral. So Funeral is an event.
It's something that we have.
So basically a Funeral is
the time when we mourn
someone who has died.
It's a celebration of their life.
Right. So it's kind of
like a ceremony where
you respect that person
that passed away, right?
Some people will talk
about the person that
passed away or maybe,
you know, it's time to
maybe honor that person too.
As you say, mourn and remember that person.
Right. So it's very
common for people in
different religions to
have different traditions.
In some religions, like
I think in Christianity,
you have a priest who
will say some things that
are very traditional and then say
some things about the person who died.
And other religions have
different ceremonies. Right.
So today we're going to take a look
at what happens in preparing a funeral.
Hi Daniel. How are you holding up?
I'm greatly sorry for your loss.
Thank you. I'm doing much better. I've
been organizing everything for the funeral.
How's that going? It's a
lot harder than I imagine.
There are many things
that you have to arrange.
I booked a time and
date with the funeral
home, but I still have
a lot of things to do.
Have you voted burial plot in a casket?
No. Wendy is being cremated. She was talked
about how she didn't want to be buried.
I already chose a cremation urn and we
planned to spread the ashes in the ocean.
I see. That sounds like something
she would have really liked.
I'm sure the memorial service will
be tasteful. You're doing a great job.
Thanks. It hasn't been easy, but luckily we
have life insurance and Wendy left behind a
detailed will that will sort
out any other legal matters.
All right. We're back.
So a pretty interesting
dialogue and I'm sure
you have a lot of questions
regarding some of those words
and phrases that you heard.
So why don't we take a look at five
key words on language takeaway?
Language takeaway. So
basically we have two friends
in this dialogue who are
discussing arrangements
for a funeral and one
friend is asking the other
about his preparations and
asks if he's bought a burial plot.
Okay. Burial plot. Now, what is a
burial plot and why would you buy one?
Well, a plot P-L-O-T plot is a piece
of land. So you can think about this,
logically, a burial
plot, burial to bury is a
place, a space in the ground
where we bury a person.
Usually you buy one of
these at a cemetery, right?
That's right. So
cemeteries have some
usually a lot of land and you
can pay for a piece of land.
A small portion. A
small portion, yeah.
And that's a burial
plot. Okay, good.
And well, our next word
is related to what you put
into this burial plot,
right? Somebody dies and
what goes into this
piece of land is a casket.
That's right. And I don't know if any of
you are fans of the TV show Six Feet Under,
but you'll know from this TV show that
there are many different kinds of caskets.
Right. So a casket is a
box. You can have fancy
caskets or you can have
wooden caskets that are
very simple, like pine.
And basically, this
is the box that the
person's body will go into
when they're buried.
Right. Very good.
So that is called a casket.
Well, moving on a new trend
I would say in many
countries and many people
around the world
don't want to be buried.
So what happens? You
get cremated. Cremated.
So this is the option for
people who are not buried.
In some countries,
China, for example, I don't
think you can be buried.
You have to be cremated
because there's an
issue of space. Right.
And this is an option for
most people where basically
your friend or your
loved one, their body is
burned and you can collect
the remains afterwards.
They're very small.
They're ashes. Right.
So it's like a burning
process. Okay, interesting.
So the word is to be
cremated to get cremated.
Yeah, his body was cremated
was cremated. And well,
as you said, you take the ashes and you can
put them in a cremation urn or just an urn.
Okay, urn. This might sound
like a strange word to you.
But an urn is a
special kind of pot,
okay, or a vessel
to hold things in.
So for example, in this case,
we have a cremation urn that
is a special pot,
usually very beautiful.
Sometimes there's a name
on it with the deceased person's
ashes or her remains.
Okay, very good.
So as you said, it's kind of
like a vase or a pot, something
very nice and small where
you have the person's ashes.
All right. So now we know what happened
during the funeral. We know what happens.
How you maybe cremate the
person or you put them in a casket.
And well, what happens
afterwards? Well afterwards,
you have a memorial service. Okay, so many
people want to know what's the difference
between a funeral and a
memorial service. Right.
In my mind, a funeral is very quiet and sad
and you have some respectful words and you
usually put the casket
into the ground or have
some kind of ceremony.
But a memorial service is
an opportunity to talk
to friends and family, to
eat some food, to have
some drinks, to talk about
the person who died. It's almost like the
party, if that makes sense. Yeah, exactly.
It's a get together of people
who obviously are trying to
give support to their
friends or their family
members who lost that
person, but also to talk
about that person in a
good way and all the great
memories they had. I
guess that's why it's called
a memorial service
because you remember and
you give out your
memories about that person.
Exactly. Okay, great. So a
lot of interesting words there.
I'm very specific
to this topic, but
obviously really important.
So why don't we go back
and listen to the
dialogue again. Hi, Daniel.
How are you holding up?
I'm greatly sorry for your loss.
Thank you. I'm doing much better. I've
been organizing everything for the funeral.
How's that going? It's a
lot harder than I imagine.
There are many things
that you have to arrange.
I booked a time and
date with the funeral
home, but I still have
a lot of things to do.
Have you voted burial
plot in a casket? No.
Wendy's being cremated.
She was talked about how she
didn't want to be
buried. I already chose a
cremation urn and we planned
to spread the ashes in the ocean.
I see. That sounds like something
she would have really liked.
I'm sure the memorial
service will be tasteful.
You're doing a great job.
Thanks. It hasn't been easy,
but luckily we have life
insurance and Wendy
left behind a detailed
will that will sort out
any other legal matters.
All right, we're back.
So we have a couple of
phrases for to be exact
that we want to take a look
at now in fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay, this first phrase
is a very useful one if you're trying to
ask someone about
maybe how they're feeling or
someone who's had
some problems recently.
You can ask them how things
are going. One person says
to the other, "Hi Daniel,
how are you holding up?
" Right. How are you holding
up? Now, you know that
to hold up something
means to have it in your
hands, but in this case
you're talking about how
are things going. Right,
but I wouldn't say, "Hey,
how are you holding up?"
Right. You wouldn't say
that to somebody, right?
If a normal circumstance.
If Marco looks really
happy, I won't ask him.
But if someone has passed
through a very difficult
period, for example, if
someone dies in their
family or perhaps if
they've been very sick or,
you know, there's
some negative or difficult
things that happen that you
can say, "How are you holding up?
" So basically means
how are you dealing
with this difficult
situation or how are you
dealing with your illness?
Okay, how are you holding
up? Or how are you
holding up with your in-laws?
Right, exactly. How are you
dealing with a difficult situation?
And then the person complemented this
by saying, and this is a very good phrase.
This whole sentence is
very useful if you want to
say something nice to a
person that has recently
lost someone, you say, "I
am greatly sorry for your loss.
" Okay, so you might
have heard the word
"loss" before, "lose."
"loss" is a noun to thing.
We normally say this
about people who have died
because you don't want to say, "I'm
really sorry for your dead brother." Right.
You know, that's sad to be
rude to direct. So in English
we say, "I'm greatly
sorry for your loss for this
part of your life that
has gone away." Right.
You can also say, "I'm
very sorry for your loss.
" This is standard phrase,
or this is a standard
phrase for funerals
and memorial services.
Exactly. So if somebody's
brother died, you go
up to that person and
you can say, "I am greatly
sorry for your loss." I am
very sorry for your loss.
That's what you say,
and it's very respectful
and it's very nice to
say. Yes, it's very nice.
All right, so now moving
on we've said that the
person is sorry and
everything, but then they
were talking about the
girl Wendy and that she had
life insurance and
that she also left behind
a detailed will. Does
that mean she forgot it?
She forgot it, but then
you can't mean that, right?
Right. Now, yeah, this is a phrase
that has a couple different meanings.
And so it's important to look at
this one when we're talking about
someone who has died,
who left behind something.
It means that they have
completed it in this case
or it survives them. Okay.
So they left that for you.
Because as you said,
it has a couple of
different meanings like
to leave behind can be too
loose or to forget. But
in this case, specifically,
it's to leave for you.
Yeah, you, for example, you
could say he died and he
left behind three children.
Okay. So that means that
he had three children when
he died and they're
still, they're still alive.
Right. Okay. Very
interesting phrase to leave
something behind. And
so she left behind a detailed
will and that's going to
sort out any other legal
matters to sort out.
This is a great verb.
This is a, well, it's a verbal
phrase that we hear a
lot with documents and
wills and things like this.
Basically to sort out
means to solve problems or
to fix or to amend. For
example, have you sorted
out that problem you
had with your plane tickets?
Mm-hmm. Okay. Yeah. To
sort out. So have you fixed
those problems or have
you solved those problems
that you had with
your plane tickets?
To sort out, to, to fix, to
make arrangements for a very,
very useful phrase.
Very useful phrase. Okay.
So four key phrases
there. Really good ones.
Why don't we go back,
listen to the dialogue and
boy back to talk a
little bit more. Hi, Daniel.
How are you holding up?
I'm greatly sorry for your loss.
Thank you. I'm
doing much better.
I've been organizing
everything for the funeral.
How's that going? It's a
lot harder than I imagine.
There are many things
that you have to arrange.
I booked a time and
date with the funeral
home, but I still have
a lot of things to do.
Have you voted burial plot in a casket?
No. When these being cremated,
she was talked about how
she didn't want to be buried.
I already chose a cremation urn and we
planned to spread the ashes in the ocean.
I see. That sounds like something
she would have really liked.
I'm sure the memorial service will
be tasteful. You're doing a great job.
Thanks. It hasn't been easy, but luckily we
have life insurance and windy left behind a
detailed will that will sort
out any other legal matters.
All right, we're back. So
now talking about funerals,
there's an interesting
word. What is it called
when a person speaks at
a funeral? Well, normally
at a funeral, a loved
one or a friend will give
a eulogy. Eulogy.
Okay, that's Eu, right? Eu.
It looks like a funny word,
but it's very important
and it's something that
you hear a lot who will
give the eulogy or his
son will give the eulogy.
So this is maybe the
keynote address in a funeral.
This is the important
speech where someone will
discuss the person who
has died and his or her
contributions and life.
Right. Okay, so that's
called a eulogy. That's
really, really interesting
because I don't know.
It's kind of a word that
you don't really use much
and you wouldn't really know it.
I have for example, I didn't really
really know about it until I saw it in a
movie when he made a
mistake. He said, "Google
eulogy" or something
like that. Oh, really?
Yeah, it was in a comedy.
But very interesting words.
It's a sad topic, but it happens
sometimes. You have to deal
with these things and
so if you have to do it in
English, well, what better
way than to learn all of
these things, which could
come in handy sometimes.
That's right. And you
never know you're watching
a movie or something
and this comes up.
There are a lot of comedies,
like you said, we call
them black comedies.
It's a very dark talk about
strange and they are like
four weddings and a funeral.
It's a very famous English
movie about this kind of thing.
And so this is useful vocabulary
and some useful phrases
for those situations as well.
Exactly. Even if you
maybe meet somebody
who I remember, I knew somebody
who met a casket salesman.
Really? Cold caskets.
It's an interesting job.
Yeah, so you never
know. You never know.
Well, I hope you've
enjoyed this lesson.
Not too dark for you, but
please do remember to ask us
any questions or practice
some of your new words
and phrases on our
website, EnglishPod.com.
All right. We'll see you guys there. Bye.